

Summary

Above all else I want to be challenged, computer programming has offered me a unique art that I love and suits my personality perfectly. I have volunteered and worked as a web developer with Assistlist.ca for 6 months implementing over a dozen features that are live on production. I am eager and confident in my new forever career as a software developer due to my passion for combining unique problem solving, creativity, and logic. A more detailed summary can be found on my website nicknewburg.ca

Employment

AssistList - Canada summer jobs

Web Developer

assistlist.ca July 2020 to Aug. 2020

Launched 5 projects in a React - Ruby on Rails environment, primarily on the front end using tools such as Semantic UI. Worked closely with a designer following exact Figma schematics.

Aug. 2012 to Apr. 2013 Chef

Worked as Garde manger/dishwasher in a high end restaurant. Preparing complex and intricate cold appetizers and salads. Simultaneously prepping for the entire kitchen while maintaining the dish area. Multitasking with a heavy sense of urgency was required on even the slowest shifts. During peak times it was a hurricane of frenzied activity.

lune 2011 to Jan 2012

Multi tasked between the dish-pit, preparation area, and the appetizer station. There was always a task to be done and efficiency and growth was a constant every shift. Sequenced the order of jobs to maximize productivity at an ever improving rate.

Volunteering

AssistList Web Developer

Mar. 2020 to Current

Working as a Web Developer in a React environment hosted by AWS. Created front-end features and dabbled in some Google Analytics tools for the marketing team to track users' likelihood to use certain features. Created and implemented 10 features that are live on production.

Gordon Neighbourhood House Tax Filer

Mar 2016 to Apr 2016

Filed personal income taxes for the elderly and disabled using Efile. Explained and chatted with those unable to understand or file their personal income tax returns.

Projects

Partners - AssistList

July 2020 to Aug. 2020

The partners page for AssistList listing all of the partners of the website.HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Semantic UI, and Ruby on

July 2020 to Aug. 2020

The resources page for AssistList including how the website works, safe exchange zones, and additional services. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Semantic UI, and Ruby on Rails.

July 2020 to July 2020 About Us - AssistList

The landing page for AssistList's about us including all sub menu sections on the top of page's navigation bar. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Semantic UI, Ruby on Rails, and React-Slick.

Jan. 2020 to Feb. 2020 <u>Portfolio</u> A deployed website featuring a biography and live demos of projects compiled into one website, Using JS, Express, HTML, CSS,

Javascript, Jquery, Node.JS, PSQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, and Knex. **PizzaShack** July 2019 to Oct. 2019

PizzaShack is a full stack web application that emulates a food ordering service. Using JS.Express, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Node.JS, PSQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, and Knex.

Apr. 2019 to May 2019

Budgestory is a full stack web app that allows users to manage their personal finances through interactive charts. It uses React, Express, PostgreSQL and a library called Highcharts.

BattleShip

Mar. 2019 to Mar. 2019

Battleship is a simple copy of the board game. It uses base technologies: HTML, CSS, and Jquery.

The Watering Hole

A full stack web application that used Express, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Ajax, Knex, Postgres, and Sessions. The application allowed used to post resources that had a description, URL, and picture for other users to view. Users could like, comment, and rate the resources.

Tweeter is a single page application built with HTML, CSS, Node, Express and Jquery, Ajax, and MongoDB resembling a Twitter clone where users can post tweets and other users may view and like those tweets.

Contact

■nicknewburg@gmail.com

nicknewburg.ca

778-384-4459 in nicknewburg/

nnewburg

Skills

LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS: Javascript, React. HTML/CSS/EJS/ERB, Jquery, Node, Java, Ruby, Docker, Rails,

VERSION CONTROL / DATABASES / ORM: Git & Github, Bit Bucket, MongoDB, PostgreSOL & Knex, Active Record.

UI & MISCELLANEOUS: Bootstrap, Semantic, Google Analytics, Mocha, Chai, Rspec

Education

LIGHTHOUSE LABS

Mar. 2019 to May 2019

Web Development Bootcamp A full-time immersive web development course.

LANGARA COLLEGE

Sept. 2013 to Sept. 2017

Business - Accounting/Computer Science Studied and achieved 30 courses of general business with a specification in accounting and computer science.

References

Tricia Pang tricia.pang@assistlist.ca

Board of Directors AssistList - Tricia serves as a founder and part of the board of directors. She manages the several different teams at Assist1 ist and orchestrates. the organization as whole with a background in project management. During my time as an employee at AssistList Tricia managed the Summer Jobs hires and acted as a project manager for our projects.

maksym.chumak@assistlist.ca 1-236-978-1662

Mentor/ DevOps Manager - Maks has acted as my mentor my entire time at AssistList both as a volunteer and employee. Helping me set up my local environment, helping with any programming questions I had, reviewing any pull requests I created, and overall being an extremely experienced and intelligent source of information and help to allow me to improve as a

Daruvin Sood daruvin.sood@assistlist.ca 604-327-8846

Board of Directors AssistList/Development Team Lead - Daruvin is the team lead or CTO of AssistList. He manages all projects and development decisions that are made. Often acting as the ambassador between teams whenever I have had to present to the Marketing team or discuss things with the Design